<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Avid Sense</title>
  <subtitle>News for the passionately insane</subtitle>
  <id>http://avidsense.com</id>
  <link href="http://avidsense.com"/>
  <link href="http://avidsense.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-03-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Baby and the Biker</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://avidsense.com/baby-and-the-biker/"/>
    <id>http://avidsense.com/baby-and-the-biker/</id>
    <published>2015-03-02T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-02T19:40:35+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Luo Bing</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="sidebar-section toc"&gt;
  &lt;h4 class="no_toc" id="contents"&gt;Contents&lt;/h4&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!--
Irony of money | Baby and the biker
* This story may or may not have happened, and may not hold any moral value whatsoever.
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s Christmas eve in ghetto Manila.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Knock knock knock”. The door swings open to reveal two old beggars who peer expectantly into the room and smile with less teeth than a premie. One has what looks to be a half smashed ukulele with some strings missing, and the other holds a frying pan with a stick in his blackened hands. Both begin to sing, strum and clang the tune to “Merry Christmas” unceremoniously and without synchrony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The host rises from his seat at the table with a look of detached frustration  &lt;!--frustrated resignation--&gt; on his face, and crosses the slum floor toward the door. He hands the old men 5 pesos and ushers them down the street toward their next mark. They depart, bowing, scraping, and hail marrying on their way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sit at a table surrounded by a bunch of shady characters dressed like bikers who were introduced to me as the extended family and aquantances of the host whom I had met at a bar earlyer that night. The vibe at the table is tense and uncomfortable, but I get the impression that that’s the norm around here. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my left is a bedroom, and peering inside all I see is a fouton on the floor with a number of children sprawled this way and that on top of it. In the bedroom doorway stands a baby no more than 2 years old who has just witnessed the transaction with the beggars, and now demands with outstretches arms; “pera! (= money in Tagalog)”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I smirk when it occurs to me that it might be his first word, but a more disturbing vision connecting the baby with the fate the old men brings me out of my thoughts and back into real-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The men siting around me ritualistically emptying tailor made cigarettes and packing them full of weed. One of them is grumbling about “shabu”. It seems he isn’t happy about the prospect of only smoking weed tonight. It’s Christmas, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How the hell did I end up here?” I ask myself, already knowing full well the reason. This is what happens when you deviate from the cobbled path in many parts of the world, even a little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The baby is screaming even louder now, with the same kind of contorted desperation you’d expect from an innocent facing execution. The noise, and to a greater degree the reason for the noise, is grating on my nerves, but everyone else just seems to ignore it. I try to say something funny to the kid, “You’ve got plenty of time to worry about money, kid. Just enjoy your life!”. Yeah right, like the kid really gives a shit about your lame attempt at humour … he’s got money on his mind, and his mind on his money!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the bikers who had given me a lift on his bike earlier looks up from the table and asks me without expression to give him 50 pesos for 1L of fuel to cover the ride. “Classy guy”, I think to myself. I’ve been buying the prick food and beers all night, and now he wants to shake me down for the rent. Looking into his eyes I search for the glimmer of a soul. Nothing, he is cold as ice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I make a conscious decision not to make a big deal out of it (I’m not really a fan of the blades guys like him carry), but as is the case the desire for a laugh often gets the better of me.
I do something stupid. I reach into my pocket and throw 5 pesos on the table in front of the man. He looks at me blankly, and I launch into my best rendition of the old beggars song complete with vocals and air guitar. 
The song a hit nerve with the other guys at the table, and they erupt with stoner laughter. I’m not sure if they understood the significance of my gesture, or if they were just laughing at my rediculous performance, but either way it was better than silence!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biker’s face turns dark and sullen. The first emotion that I’d noticed on him flickers into view; repressed rage. He’s not handling the ridicule very well. His mates are biting even harder now, and they start throwing objects at eachother from across the table. Sensing the distraction, and an imminent climax &lt;!-- downfall --&gt; to the festivities on this most holy of nights, I take my queue and make a quick deparure through the front door without uttering a word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walk away briskly, using the labyrinthine slum to obscure the line of sight from the doorway while simultaneously looking back over my shoulder and avoiding puddles of pig shit. As I walk I realise that everyone in the room was laughing except for the baby and the biker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hahahahahahahaa! Suckers…&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Downside of Marijuana Legalisation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://avidsense.com/downside-of-marijuana-legalisation/"/>
    <id>http://avidsense.com/downside-of-marijuana-legalisation/</id>
    <published>2015-02-28T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-02-28T15:14:30+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Luo Bing</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;!--
TODO:
- more facts and figures!
--&gt;

&lt;div class="sidebar-section toc"&gt;
  &lt;h4 class="no_toc" id="contents"&gt;Contents&lt;/h4&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m no journalist, so on occasion I take the liberty of indulging in opinion. However, my integrity dictates that I would never put forward an opinion unless it was based on actual empirical knowledge (the only kind worth a damn), and untainted by any social or dogmatic system of belief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to smoke pot - a lot of pot - and while I no longer partake of &lt;em&gt;da erb&lt;/em&gt; myself, I still associate with people who are regular long time smokers. What I notice about these people is that they perceive themselves as liberated free thinkers, but spouting anti-establishment propaganda does not make you a free thinker, it makes you part of the problem. Of course, being part of the solution isn’t easy when you view the world through a purple haze. I love my pot-head friends, but conversations with them can be best characterised as; strongly opinionated, cyclic and repetitive. I call them &lt;em&gt;loopy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what’s with people going around saying that pot is good for you? &lt;a href="http://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMra1402309"&gt;Pot makes you stupid&lt;/a&gt;. People who day otherwise are fools guided by populist propaganda or some instinctive brand of juvenile rebellion, and need to shut up. Sure, pot may be beneficial for people with emphysema or undergoing chemo treatments, and even for the occasional chill out session, but the irony of marijuana is that when it’s smoked &lt;em&gt;too frequently&lt;/em&gt; it deprives one of the very motivation and keen mental edge required for creative productivity and insight that it’s commonly solicited as heightening. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other issue with legalisation is that while it may be great for the economy and open many new opportunities and markets, it will also mean harsher penalties for growing and distributing marijuana without government permission, because it will be classed as a taxable commodity. For example, growing marijuana illegally with intent to sell prior to legislation would be a felony offense with a small fine or prison sentence, but after legalisation it will be tax fraud with huge fines, confiscation of property, and extended prison sentences. &lt;!-- If this is your area of enterprise, then legalisation might be a good que to switch, otherwise be prepared to answer to federal charges of tax evasion as well as the tokin (cough) felony. --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, you make up your own mind. As with all matters concerning temptation, one must exercise one’s best judgment. In other words this means understanding the nature of the beast, and keeping that beast on just enough rope lest it run wild ravaging and desecrating everything in sight. If you haven’t seen &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0387808/"&gt;Idiorcacy&lt;/a&gt; yet then I recommend you watch out. It’s one of the worst films ever made, and that’s exactly why you should see it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Marijuana Business Opportunities</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://avidsense.com/marijuana-legalisation-and-business-opportunities/"/>
    <id>http://avidsense.com/marijuana-legalisation-and-business-opportunities/</id>
    <published>2015-02-26T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-02-28T15:11:45+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Luo Bing</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="sidebar-section toc"&gt;
  &lt;h4 class="no_toc" id="contents"&gt;Contents&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul id="markdown-toc"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#rapid-growth"&gt;Rapid Growth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#downside-of-legalisation"&gt;Downside of Legalisation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Widespread legalisation and increased media coverage is changing public perception about weed, and the profiteers are gathering &lt;!--through the purple haze like--&gt; stoners to a fat joint as the red light turns green for the legal weed business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Progressive governments around the world are chomping at the bit for the opportunity to legalise marijuana. Hell why not, with the economy in a ditch worldwide they sure could use another taxable commodity, and &lt;a href="https://webcom.colostate.edu/coloradofutures/files/2013/04/CFC-Amendment-64-Study-final2.pdf"&gt;everyone is smoking&lt;/a&gt; it anyway, right? Weather or not this is a good thing is debatable, but entrepreneurs and investors are all on &lt;a href="http://www.thedailybell.com/printview/params/id/36066/printview/"&gt;High Alert&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="rapid-growth"&gt;Rapid Growth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every entrepreneur dreams of discovering an untapped market where they could enter with a low initial outlay and have a huge potential for growth. It’s not very often that an industry boom takes place in the current world economy&lt;!--, especially due to the changing legal landscape--&gt;, so it’s no surprise that entrepreneurs and investors are jumping on board and cannabis related businesses being hailed one of the best startup opportunities for 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
First off, lets take a look at some facts and figures from [Factbook publisher Cannabusiness Media](), pertaining to the U.S. legal-pot sector. 
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, lets take a look at some facts and figures pertaining to the burgeoning U.S. legal-pot sector. The following information was published in a &lt;a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/caroltice/2015/02/05/why-legal-cannabis-is-2015s-best-startup-opportunity/"&gt;recent Forbes article&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In 2014, it’s estimated that between $1.6 billion and $1.9 billion of legal pot sold for medical use in the U.S., and another $600 million to $700 million was sold for legal, recreational use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Factbook also projects that legal cannabis businesses will do roughly $8 billion in revenue by 2018. So that’s more than $7 billion of upside potential in the near-term marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The competitive landscape is full of young companies, too. Less than half are even three years old, the Factbook found. Of the rest, 4% of the businesses surveyed reported they started in 2012, 21% launched in 2013, and 30% are a year old or less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Most businesses report their startup costs were modest. One-third of cannabis wholesalers say they put in less than $50,000. Some 14% spent between $50,000-$100,000, and 24% spent between $100,000-$500,000. The remaining 29% spent $500,000 or more, with just 10% of those reporting they spent over $1 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For such a young industry, it’s notable how many of the companies report they are profitable. The Factbook found over half are already operating in the black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The full breakdown:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Only 3% said they are seeing “significant losses”&lt;br /&gt;
15% are “losing some money”&lt;br /&gt;
28% report they’re at break even&lt;br /&gt;
38% are “modestly profitable”&lt;br /&gt;
16% report they are “very profitable”&lt;br /&gt;
Profitability is coming quickly, too — 62% of the businesses said they were profitable within 12 months. Only 6% said it took more than 3 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One final reason legal cannabis is a desirable sector to enter: customers spend big. While Americans famously spend an average of over $1,500 a year on their pets, a cannabis consumer spends $1,869 on their habit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are quite remarkable figures for a sector that investors wouldn’t touch with a 10 foot stem just a couple of years ago. Angel investors and venture capitalists have obviously smelled the green, because they have started jumping in and backing cannabis companies, with quite a few pot startups already raising over $1 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the entrepreneur, the cannabis industry holds many opportunities, from seed to consumable and everything thereabouts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultivator/Farmer&lt;/strong&gt;: Someone has to &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/amanda-reiman/cannabis-farming_b_5481378.html"&gt;grow the weed&lt;/a&gt;, and the doors are opening due to the changing legal landscape&lt;!--for those with genuine know-how who can grow the best product--&gt;. Of course, obtaining a licence to grow dope legally won’t be easy, and you can count on there being a tonne of read tape to hinder your efforts, but in some parts of the world &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Legal_and_medical_status_of_cannabis"&gt;it’s entirely possible&lt;/a&gt;. However, legalisation will most likely spell &lt;a href="/downside-of-marijuana-legalisation"&gt;harsher regulations and penalties&lt;/a&gt; for those that continue to grow without government permission.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seed Harvester/Retailer&lt;/strong&gt;: Quality is everything in the weed business, so naturally there’s a strong demand for the highest quality seeds. This spells opportunity for entrepreneurs who know their strains and can procure seeds from top growers&lt;!-- and supply the best seeds--&gt;. Depending on where you are based there may well be legal loopholes that enable you to sell seeds legally.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edible Creator&lt;/strong&gt;: Edible creation is one of the more interesting and &lt;a href="https://www.colorado.gov/pacific/sites/default/files/2014%20MED%20Annual%20Update.pdf"&gt;potentially lucrative&lt;/a&gt; careers in the industry. There’s already a lot of businesses out there creating amazing edibles in the form of; cakes, candies, coffee and teas, drinks and more. Your imagination is the limit, and the more creativity you have the better. &lt;!--A trip to the local medical dispensary or retailer will leave most people dazzled by the number of options available; cakes, candies, coffee and teas, drinks and more.--&gt; Again, tight regulations and stringent content listing specifications need to be observed, so you’d “better call Saul” before going out and investing in a new kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concentrates Processor&lt;/strong&gt;: Concentrates include things like hash and oil products which are in high demand, and can also be very lucrative. These products are noted for their incredibly high concentration, which can have powerful effects and be very valuable to medical cannabis patients. A background in chemistry is helpful, and access to laboratory equipment is be necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Retail Store&lt;/strong&gt;:This is the ultimate dream for marijuana entrepreneurs - to be able to stock the green gold, and all it’s related derivatives and creations. While the laws in your are probably won’t allow for just anyone to open a retail store, these laws will be under constant review as the industry opens up. Conversely, changing laws can pose a significant risk to retail outlets&lt;!--, but it could also be the perfect opportunity to get in early--&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glass Merchant&lt;/strong&gt;: Glass merchants have been around for a long time thanks to the loophole in most countries that permit the sale and ownership of unused pot smoking utensils. An ornate bong is a pot head’s pride and joy, so if you’re doing something a little creative and unique then there is a lot of opportunity here - sans the legal risk.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Courier Services&lt;/strong&gt;: Delivery services will be essential for every dispensary, as many customers with medical conditions won’t be able to physically make it to the shop, and the rest will likely be too paralytic on the latest chronic to drive.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security Services&lt;/strong&gt;: Security is a primary concern for cannabis related retailers and storage locations, and is a great area for specialisation if you’re already established in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tourism&lt;/strong&gt;: Around the world there are many popular marijuana related festivals. The &lt;a href="http://www.nimbinmardigrass.com/"&gt;Mardigrass&lt;/a&gt; in Numbin, Australia comes to mind: It’s a magical time where once a year the police stop arresting people for smoking on the street, and everybody comes together in a smokey haze to bask in their love for ganja. There could also be a lot of opportunity for tours too; think winery tours but for cannabis farms. &lt;!--
Marijuana has a wonderful ability to bring people together in a smokey haze, and there is no shortage of people who are willing to part with their last 3 months of pay ckecks to sample the finest wares.
--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web &amp;amp; Software&lt;/strong&gt;:
The potential for web and software development companies in this industry is huge, and a bunch of companies like Leafly, Viridian Sciences and WeedMaps are already blazing a trail.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Online platforms for education, sales and communities&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mobile apps for stoners&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Accounting and product management systems&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consultants&lt;/strong&gt;: The market boom will open with it many opportunities for consultants who can provide valuable experience and insight, and genuine empirical knowledge will most likely be in short supply and high demand due to the previously illicit status of the market. &lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Farming consultants will be in high demand, as a high quality crop is essential to the success of a farm. &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Entrepreneurs will need help getting their businesses off the ground, and to help identify areas for growth and expansion.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Marketing consultants who understand the culture can assist cannabis startups get their brands off the ground, and create a real identity for businesses in the industry.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s still relatively early days, and although there are already some established big players, opportunities abound in the marijuana industry. Don’t be blinded by the northern lights though, it’s still a risky business; legal changes could change the game overnight, and a glut from the early market boom could &lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2015/01/16/washington-state-growers-struggling-to-sell-legal-marijuana/"&gt;slow things down&lt;/a&gt; considerably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="downside-of-legalisation"&gt;Downside of Legalisation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m no journalist, so on occasion I take the liberty of indulging in opinion. However, my integrity dictates that I would never put forward an opinion unless it was based on actual empirical knowledge (the only kind worth a damn), and untainted by any social or dogmatic system of belief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to smoke pot - a lot of pot - and while I no longer partake of &lt;em&gt;da erb&lt;/em&gt; myself, I still associate with people who are regular long time smokers. What I notice about these people is that they perceive themselves as liberated free thinkers, but spouting anti-establishment propaganda does not make you a free thinker, it makes you part of the problem. Of course, being part of the solution isn’t easy when you view the world through a purple haze. I love my pot-head friends, but conversations with them can be best characterised as; strongly opinionated, cyclic and repetitive. I call them &lt;em&gt;loopy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what’s with people going around saying that pot is good for you? &lt;a href="http://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMra1402309"&gt;Pot makes you stupid&lt;/a&gt;. People who day otherwise are fools guided by populist propaganda or some instinctive brand of juvenile rebellion, and need to shut up. Sure, pot may be beneficial for people with emphysema or undergoing chemo treatments, and even for the occasional chill out session, but the irony of marijuana is that when it’s smoked &lt;em&gt;too frequently&lt;/em&gt; it deprives one of the very motivation and keen mental edge required for creative productivity and insight that it’s commonly solicited as heightening. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other issue with legalisation is that while it may be great for the economy and open many new opportunities and markets, it will also mean harsher penalties for growing and distributing marijuana without government permission, because it will be classed as a taxable commodity. For example, growing marijuana illegally with intent to sell prior to legislation would be a felony offense with a small fine or prison sentence, but after legalisation it will be tax fraud with huge fines, confiscation of property, and extended prison sentences. &lt;!-- If this is your area of enterprise, then legalisation might be a good que to switch, otherwise be prepared to answer to federal charges of tax evasion as well as the tokin (cough) felony. --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, you make up your own mind. As with all matters concerning temptation, one must exercise one’s best judgment. In other words this means understanding the nature of the beast, and keeping that beast on just enough rope lest it run wild ravaging and desecrating everything in sight. If you haven’t seen &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0387808/"&gt;Idiorcacy&lt;/a&gt; yet then I recommend you watch out. It’s one of the worst films ever made, and that’s exactly why you should see it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Living for Purpose</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://avidsense.com/living-for-purpose/"/>
    <id>http://avidsense.com/living-for-purpose/</id>
    <published>2015-02-17T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-02-19T17:06:30+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Luo Bing</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="sidebar-section toc"&gt;
  &lt;h4 class="no_toc" id="contents"&gt;Contents&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul id="markdown-toc"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#disambiguation-and-explanation"&gt;Disambiguation and Explanation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#false-idols"&gt;False Idols&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#the-power-of-purpose"&gt;The Power of Purpose&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions like “why are we here”, “where did we come from” and “what is god” are largely redundant. Such questions they may never be answered, and the answers probably wouldn’t change anything anyway. What really matters is the state of our current existentiality, because for damn sure we can do something about that&lt;!--, and we must be answerable for the way we live our lives--&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
When used in relation to one's life
This misunderstanding is a good basis with which to clarify the difference between purpose and career.
Such is the joy of squiring knowledge, and the limitation of language.
--&gt;

&lt;h2 id="disambiguation-and-explanation"&gt;Disambiguation and Explanation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The word “purpose” is used to describe the reason for which something exists, so when used in relation to one’s life, it means quite simply the “reason for one’s existence”. Therefore, “living for purpose” is the act of living for a something greater than ourselves. It could be said that soldier in the army “serves a purpose”, and that would be technically correct, but that concept of purpose is inherently different the concept of “living for purpose” posed by this article, which is unique to the sovereign &lt;!--and conscious--&gt; individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
This is entirely the case, but when one broadens the avenue of study and delves deeper into the nature of a concept, the terminology used to describe the concept takes on a whole new meaning. 
The idea may seem primarily functional and practical for those who haven't exercised or given it much thought, but the
--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who practice “living for purpose”, live by a profound existential philosophy than runs much deeper than the functional conotation of “purpose”. Purpose becomes one’s very reason for drawing breath - the driving force behind one’s every thought and action. This is because the person of purpose understands that highest aim for a human life is to live for purpose, and that we are all accountable for the way we live our lives. Many people would look upon this kind of attitude and judge it as “obsessive” and “fanatical”, but on the whole these people don’t and can’t understand what it is to live for something greater &lt;!-- themselves or a --&gt; than a preconception. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who perceive the world &lt;!-- life --&gt; through the matrix of their individual preconceptions are affected by them in every thought and deed. Since purpose is not defined at the scope of the individual, it is impossible for affected individuals to comprehend what it means to live a life of purpose. Thus, a life of true purpose is only obtainable by the &lt;a href="/matrix-of-misconception"&gt;free and awakened individual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, true purpose if not bound by a specific outcome. This is a very challenging concept for people to grasp, because we’ve been conditioned to expect payment for our efforts, either by way of financial or energetic exchange. If you’re asking “what’s in it for me?”, then you’re not living for purpose, you’re living for your own concerns. As soon as it becomes about what you’re going to “get”, then true purpose becomes tainted. There’s nothing wrong with that, it’s what makes the world go round in it’s current dysfunctional state, but don’t be mistaken, it’s not true purpose. With purpose as a guide, one acts simply because one can, and because it’s the right thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
argued that they serve a purpose,
Read: [Matrix of Misconception]()
--&gt;

&lt;!--

This way of living and thinking is so foreign and strange to people because the  wayward, notably the economy, has us geared up to chase our own tails 




For those who live a life with no purpose, the definition of "purpose" will always be primarily functional and practical, but for the minority who live a life of purpose, the meaning is somewhat more profound. Purpose becomes one's very reason for drawing breath, the driving force behind one's every thought and action. This is because the highest aim for a human life, is to live for purpose, and we are all accountable for how we live our lives.

Furthermore, true purpose if not bound by a specific outcome. This is a hard concept for many to grasp, because we've been conditioned to expect payment for our efforts, either by way of financial or energetic exchange. If you're asking "what's in it for me?", then you're not living for purpose, you're living for your own concerns. As soon as it becomes about what you're going to "get", then the purpose is no longer true. There's nothing wrong with this, it's what makes the world go round in it's current dysfunctional state, but don't be mistaken, this isn't true purpose. With purpose as a guide, one acts simply because one can, and because it's the right thing to do.

This way of living and thinking is so foreign and strange to people because the way 
--&gt;

&lt;!--, and as so is often used reflectively to describe one's prominent contribution or "life's work".--&gt;
&lt;!--
For those who live a life with no purpose, the definition of "purpose" will always be primarily functional and practical, but for the minority who live a life of purpose, the meaning is somewhat more profound. 
--&gt;
&lt;!--

It is therefore, easy to mistake purpose for dedication. The difference lies in the intent and motivation behind our actions. (selfish example, apparently selfless, but not purpose because tied to outcome)
The meaning of purpose is "living one's life for the greater good, and knowing one's role to play in the unfolding prophecy"
The mind of preconception will look very hard, and observe the progress of change, but it will be unable to comprehend the "je ne siqua" of the individual embodying purpose.

(not defined at the scope of the individual)
(nothing great was ever achieved by idle hands and minds)
(individual and greater good disambiguation)
(great men are made immortal by their ability to ... black sails)
--&gt;

&lt;h2 id="false-idols"&gt;False Idols&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no end of so-called prophets and gurus out there masquerading as peddlers of truth. These types of gurus speak with great conviction and charisma, and prey on the weak minded and impressionable lost souls who’re seeking answers. Of course, the only outcome is further distraction and confusion from truth. Any man who would elevate himself above others, glorify himself, enforce worship, or inspire followers through fear, insecurity or rage, should never be trusted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dedication to a passion or goal should not be confused with purpose. When it comes to truth, even 1% off is dangerous, &lt;!-- and it may have disastrous affects --&gt; and may be difficult or impossible to distinguish for the uninitiated. Some of the worst attrocities have been comitted by dedicated and charismatic men who saw themselves as godlike, and were deluded enough to think what they were doing the “right thing”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world is full of cases of the blind leading the blind, and it must be exposed, not proliferated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
It is therefore relevant to say that a person of purpose is responsible for holding a space which others can aspire too.
Purpose does not mean great passion.
This gives rise to the potential for false prophets and gurus.

(a little bit of knowledge is a dangerous thing)

The mind of preconception will look very hard, and observe the progress of change, but it will be unable to comprehend the "je ne siqua" of the individual embodying purpose.
--&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-power-of-purpose"&gt;The Power of Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an individual to hold a position of purpose is a very powerful thing, but when purpose is shared between a man and a woman the effects are multiplied many times. The combination of masculine drive and female creation united under a common purpose is a sacred bond with the power to achieve the impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nature of purpose is that in essence it’s impeccable and incorruptible, and therefore inspires similar traits in those is affects. This kind of intent speaks to people on a primal level, and is powerful enough to topple governments if assimilated on a large scale. This kind of revolution is far superior to a violent uprising, which only serves to precipitate the cycle of oppression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mankind is almost ready for a new precedent, and the global information network is ready to spread it to the four corners of the earth when it takes place.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Matrix of Misconception</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://avidsense.com/matrix-of-misconception/"/>
    <id>http://avidsense.com/matrix-of-misconception/</id>
    <published>2015-02-16T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-02-19T17:09:32+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Luo Bing</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="sidebar-section toc"&gt;
  &lt;h4 class="no_toc" id="contents"&gt;Contents&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul id="markdown-toc"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#mental-conditioning"&gt;Mental Conditioning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#awakening"&gt;Awakening&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The matrix of misconception exists in the world that confronts us every time we step out of the front door into the world at large. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serfs fill the multi-cultural slave ships dreaming of a better day, men in suits file in and out of skyscrapers looking solely upward, and consumers line the streets taking well branded poison while flaunting cloned individuality.
Each one chasing empty dreams confined by the boundaries the matrix, each one profoundly helpless&lt;!-- secretly wallowing in an sense of profound helplessness--&gt;. Only the most misconceived ego may prosper. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="mental-conditioning"&gt;Mental Conditioning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the time of our birth we are conditioned with a sense of duality that is the foundation of the matrix, and the fundamental disconnect from true existence. Our parents, politicians, language, education, economy, even ourselves, and indeed the system as a whole, are all guilty. Everything is labeled; he is “smart”, she is “dumb”, that is “good” or “bad”. We are taught to aspire to the attainment of wealth and title in a system that’s redundant for the evolving consciousness. This is perfect for the people who run the world because they can go about their business unhindered, while we’re inexorably embroiled in our own self fulfilling prophecies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
busy chasing our tails 
, to validate our actions in the eyes of other's scrutiny.

This is the way it's been set up for us. Our society, notably the economy, has us geared up to chase our own tails in a self fulfilling prophecy until we die. 

for this world of misconception. 
We are conditioned
causes a fundamental disconnect between the 
Our mind is filled concepts of duality and we are raised with a sense of duality 
superfluous 
with superfluous distractions which breeds contempt and duality
segregated 
--&gt;

&lt;!--
, (poverty ghetto),  filled with a sense of their own self importance
Skyscrapers line the skyways as

Towers line the skyways, standing almost as tall as the men in suits housed within.
 --&gt;

&lt;h2 id="awakening"&gt;Awakening&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awakening refers to the attainment of a state of consciousness &lt;!--by an individual or collective--&gt; that’s &lt;!--unfettered by--&gt;free from preconception and manipulation. The process is roughly as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Awareness&lt;/strong&gt;: One begins to glimpse the reality behind the veil.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commitment&lt;/strong&gt;: A commitment is made to living consciously. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Awakening&lt;/strong&gt;: Consciousness shifts and the mind awakens. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: The only path for an awakened mind is a &lt;a href="/living-for-purpose"&gt;life of purpose&lt;/a&gt;. Very few people on the planet live like this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True awakening is more than just understanding the framework of lies that surrounds us, it’s about reprogramming the mind and body to be free and &lt;!--protected against--&gt;immune to it’s contagion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the stage of incipient metamorphosis it can be nearly impossible to see the causality of our actions, and people have a tendency of becoming raving “conspiracy theorists”. This doesn’t help anyone, and it only serves to strengthen resistance to change&lt;!--, and the position of the opposition--&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To attempt to “awaken” someone whose psychological construct is totally dependent on the matrix of misconception is bound to have unpredictable consequences, kind of like trying to push 10,000v through a speaker cable. Therefore, people need to be have some kind of inherent structure in place, an alternative to replace the matrix when it collapses. This structure can be localised to the individual or a network of awakened individuals who can provide fortification. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article is a work in progress… &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Forum Government</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://avidsense.com/forum-government/"/>
    <id>http://avidsense.com/forum-government/</id>
    <published>2015-02-09T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-02-17T13:54:22+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="sidebar-section toc"&gt;
  &lt;h4 class="no_toc" id="contents"&gt;Contents&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul id="markdown-toc"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#back-to-basics"&gt;Back to Basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#the-nature-of-the-beast"&gt;The Nature of the Beast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#the-2080-rule"&gt;The 20%/80% Rule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#our-only-chance"&gt;Our Only Chance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humanity now confronts a range of unprecedented problems including pollution of land, sea and air, climate change and developing shortages of fuel, food and water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we collectively grapple with these issues with all the finesse of a drunken sailor, it might just behoove us to go back to first principles and analyse why we struggle with them and what a rational species might do under these circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite simply, we struggle because we are selfish and incapable of making decisions for the greater good. Because of this multi-faceted selfishness, we could very easily render our planet uninhabitable during this century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this score, the new age movement and fundamentalist Christians share some common ground. The new age movement looks to the ancient Mayan calendar and December 2012 as the end of an age, while millions of Christians believe we are in the end-times, with Armageddon a few short years away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However it is not just these spiritual and religious groups that believe our way of living must come to an end. It is a belief commonly held by a significant proportion, if not a majority of socially aware people around the globe, that our current situation is hopeless and that some sort of cataclysm is necessary if we are to birth a new and better reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The irony is that world-wide we have millions of highly intelligent people with brilliant ideas that have the potential to create a wonderful new paradigm in every facet of our lives. These same people almost invariably feel disenfranchised and apathetic, while a tiny minority controlled by vested interests drives us further into the mire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we are to survive, let alone prosper, we must now develop new, more intelligent ways of governing ourselves, so that we learn to harness and benefit from this phenomenal resource. Our only hope now is to learn how to objectively develop policies that are based on the best of our combined thought processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="back-to-basics"&gt;Back to Basics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The justification for this is simple. If there were 100 of us left on Earth, huddled up in a cave, pondering our future, would we want to elect and pay someone to do our thinking for us, or would we want to hold a facilitated meeting that would synergise the best of our ideas? Not much of a choice, is it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forum Government is a new concept and consequently not much thought has gone into it. &lt;!-- (Let’s give full marks to the Australian Prime Minister, Mr. Rudd for at least acknowledging the relevance of community involvement at the national level.) --&gt; In practice, it requires an objective evaluation process according to a set of predetermined core values. These values should reflect our highest potential and could include, for example, innovation, empowerment, open co-operation, self-sufficiency and sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each submitted idea or variation of an idea is rated by a panel of qualified experts, with each government portfolio having it’s own panel. Governments are elected on the basis of the core values they espouse, rather than the promises they make, the difference being that there is no longer a direct connection between politician and outcome. That equates with less scope for corruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With computers we have the potential to implement Forum Government. Certainly we need to develop the software to make it fair, workable and incorruptible, however once the Bill Gates’ of our world set their minds to it, it will quickly become practicable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we must insist on it, in the knowledge that it is ultimately irresistible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-nature-of-the-beast"&gt;The Nature of the Beast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all our recent technological advancements, we humans are a pretty pathetic bunch. We have promoted ourselves to our level of incompetency and are quite simply unfit to be in control of this planet. This is what so many of us know in our heart of hearts. It’s not that we’re all rotten, it just that the way we govern ourselves belongs in the dark ages and it’s hard to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humanity is capable of supreme altruism, heroism and concerted action, especially when all else has failed. There can be little doubt that those qualities will kick in when we reach that stage. Though we are probably there right now, the pain is not yet great enough. Denial prevails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our current world situation, it is difficult to know what that stage looks like. My guess is we’ll need to endure the suffering of the loss of a significant % of the population. Impoverishment of the wealthy is another criterion and we’re going down that road right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there is an intermediate stage we must pass through before crying enough and stepping into our inherent greatness. That is the stage of the one world government, the pinnacle of globalization and all the other dehumanizing polices that are turning our world into a soup kitchen with insufficient soup. Rest assured, the blueprint of the ultimate prize is waiting in the wings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-2080-rule"&gt;The 20%/80% Rule&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humanity is controlled though fear. Just as a small child instinctively knows how to manipulate it’s parents, so do our political leaders know they can persuade us to follow a course of action by making us afraid of the consequences of it’s alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are those whose intellect allows them to transcend that to a greater or lesser extent, however they are a distinct minority, say, 20%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we have a bizarre situation in which the “will” of the “unthinking” 80% can be easily manipulated to swamp the superior thinking of the 20%, implementing policies and agendas that serve only a powerful few, who are beholding to their peers, with little regard for the opinions of the masses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;History is replete with examples of nations unjustly waging war on other nations, supported by a majority which has been made afraid of the consequences of not doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is obvious and anyone reading this article will know it to be true. It is the nature of things on planetarium Earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is why democracy must now die… &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="our-only-chance"&gt;Our Only Chance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tiny window of opportunity exists for us to turn our future around. We have the opportunity, right now, to investigate and develop the mechanisms that will enable to shrug off our sense of fear, apathy and doom; the very mechanisms that we will need when we reach the critical stage outlined above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forum government can’t and won’t happen now. The death throes of the old, tried and false have just begun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is a lot of work to be done developing computer models for objective policy making, based on diverse inputs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For there will surely soon come a time when the metaphorical 100 will need them.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
