<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Avid Sense</title>
  <subtitle>News for the passionately insane</subtitle>
  <id>http://avidsense.com</id>
  <link href="http://avidsense.com"/>
  <link href="http://avidsense.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-02-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Living for Purpose</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://avidsense.com/living-for-purpose/"/>
    <id>http://avidsense.com/living-for-purpose/</id>
    <published>2015-02-17T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-02-19T16:51:22+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Luo Bing</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="sidebar-section toc"&gt;
  &lt;h4 class="no_toc" id="contents"&gt;Contents&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul id="markdown-toc"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#disambiguation-and-explanation"&gt;Disambiguation and Explanation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#false-idols"&gt;False Idols&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#the-power-of-purpose"&gt;The Power of Purpose&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions like “why are we here”, “where did we come from” and “what is god” are largely redundant. Such questions they may never be answered, and the answers probably wouldn’t change anything anyway. What really matters is the state of our current existentiality, because for damn sure we can do something about that&lt;!--, and we must be answerable for the way we live our lives--&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
When used in relation to one's life
This misunderstanding is a good basis with which to clarify the difference between purpose and career.
Such is the joy of squiring knowledge, and the limitation of language.
--&gt;

&lt;h2 id="disambiguation-and-explanation"&gt;Disambiguation and Explanation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The word “purpose” is used to describe the reason for which something exists, so when used in relation to one’s life, it means quite simply the “reason for one’s existence”. Therefore, “living for purpose” is the act of living for a something greater than ourselves. It could be said that soldier in the army “serves a purpose”, and that would be technically correct, but that concept of purpose is inherently different the concept of “living for purpose” posed by this article, which is unique to the sovereign &lt;!--and conscious--&gt; individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
This is entirely the case, but when one broadens the avenue of study and delves deeper into the nature of a concept, the terminology used to describe the concept takes on a whole new meaning. 
The idea may seem primarily functional and practical for those who haven't exercised or given it much thought, but the
--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who practice “living for purpose”, live by a profound existential philosophy than runs much deeper than the functional conotation of “purpose”. Purpose becomes one’s very reason for drawing breath - the driving force behind one’s every thought and action. This is because the person of purpose understands that highest aim for a human life is to live for purpose, and that we are all accountable for the way we live our lives. Many people would look upon this kind of attitude and judge it as “obsessive” and “fanatical”, but on the whole these people don’t and can’t understand what it is to live for something greater &lt;!-- themselves or a --&gt; than a preconception. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who perceive the world &lt;!-- life --&gt; through the matrix of their individual preconceptions are affected by them in every thought and deed. Since purpose is not defined at the scope of the individual, it is impossible for affected individuals to comprehend what it means to live a life of purpose. Thus, a life of true purpose is only obtainable by the &lt;a href=""&gt;free and awakened individual&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, true purpose if not bound by a specific outcome. This is a very challenging concept for people to grasp, because we’ve been conditioned to expect payment for our efforts, either by way of financial or energetic exchange. If you’re asking “what’s in it for me?”, then you’re not living for purpose, you’re living for your own concerns. As soon as it becomes about what you’re going to “get”, then true purpose becomes tainted. There’s nothing wrong with that, it’s what makes the world go round in it’s current dysfunctional state, but don’t be mistaken, it’s not true purpose. With purpose as a guide, one acts simply because one can, and because it’s the right thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
argued that they serve a purpose,
Read: [Matrix of Misconception]()
--&gt;

&lt;!--

This way of living and thinking is so foreign and strange to people because the  wayward, notably the economy, has us geared up to chase our own tails 




For those who live a life with no purpose, the definition of "purpose" will always be primarily functional and practical, but for the minority who live a life of purpose, the meaning is somewhat more profound. Purpose becomes one's very reason for drawing breath, the driving force behind one's every thought and action. This is because the highest aim for a human life, is to live for purpose, and we are all accountable for how we live our lives.

Furthermore, true purpose if not bound by a specific outcome. This is a hard concept for many to grasp, because we've been conditioned to expect payment for our efforts, either by way of financial or energetic exchange. If you're asking "what's in it for me?", then you're not living for purpose, you're living for your own concerns. As soon as it becomes about what you're going to "get", then the purpose is no longer true. There's nothing wrong with this, it's what makes the world go round in it's current dysfunctional state, but don't be mistaken, this isn't true purpose. With purpose as a guide, one acts simply because one can, and because it's the right thing to do.

This way of living and thinking is so foreign and strange to people because the way 
--&gt;

&lt;!--, and as so is often used reflectively to describe one's prominent contribution or "life's work".--&gt;
&lt;!--
For those who live a life with no purpose, the definition of "purpose" will always be primarily functional and practical, but for the minority who live a life of purpose, the meaning is somewhat more profound. 
--&gt;
&lt;!--

It is therefore, easy to mistake purpose for dedication. The difference lies in the intent and motivation behind our actions. (selfish example, apparently selfless, but not purpose because tied to outcome)
The meaning of purpose is "living one's life for the greater good, and knowing one's role to play in the unfolding prophecy"
The mind of preconception will look very hard, and observe the progress of change, but it will be unable to comprehend the "je ne siqua" of the individual embodying purpose.

(not defined at the scope of the individual)
(nothing great was ever achieved by idle hands and minds)
(individual and greater good disambiguation)
(great men are made immortal by their ability to ... black sails)
--&gt;

&lt;h2 id="false-idols"&gt;False Idols&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no end of so-called prophets and gurus out there masquerading as peddlers of truth. These types of gurus speak with great conviction and charisma, and prey on the weak minded and impressionable lost souls who’re seeking answers. Of course, the only outcome is further distraction and confusion from truth. Any man who would elevate himself above others, glorify himself, enforce worship, or inspire followers through fear, insecurity or rage, should never be trusted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dedication to a passion or goal should not be confused with purpose. When it comes to truth, even 1% off is dangerous, &lt;!-- and it may have disastrous affects --&gt; and may be difficult or impossible to distinguish for the uninitiated. Some of the worst attrocities have been comitted by dedicated and charismatic men who saw themselves as godlike, and were deluded enough to think what they were doing the “right thing”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world is full of cases of the blind leading the blind, and it must be exposed, not proliferated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
It is therefore relevant to say that a person of purpose is responsible for holding a space which others can aspire too.
Purpose does not mean great passion.
This gives rise to the potential for false prophets and gurus.

(a little bit of knowledge is a dangerous thing)

The mind of preconception will look very hard, and observe the progress of change, but it will be unable to comprehend the "je ne siqua" of the individual embodying purpose.
--&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-power-of-purpose"&gt;The Power of Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an individual to hold a position of purpose is a very powerful thing, but when purpose is shared between a man and a woman the effects are multiplied many times. The combination of masculine drive and female creation united under a common purpose is a sacred bond with the power to achieve the impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nature of purpose is that in essence it’s impeccable and incorruptible, and therefore inspires similar traits in those is affects. This kind of intent speaks to people on a primal level, and is powerful enough to topple governments if assimilated on a large scale. This kind of revolution is far superior to a violent uprising, which only serves to precipitate the cycle of oppression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mankind is almost ready for a new precedent, and the global information network is ready to spread it to the four corners of the earth when it takes place.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Matrix of Misconception</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://avidsense.com/matrix-of-misconception/"/>
    <id>http://avidsense.com/matrix-of-misconception/</id>
    <published>2015-02-16T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-02-17T13:58:27+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Luo Bing</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="sidebar-section toc"&gt;
  &lt;h4 class="no_toc" id="contents"&gt;Contents&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul id="markdown-toc"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#mental-conditioning"&gt;Mental Conditioning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#awakening"&gt;Awakening&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The matrix of misconception exists in the world that confronts us every time we step out of the front door into the world at large. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serfs fill the multi-cultural slave ships dreaming of a better day, men in suits file in and out of skyscrapers looking solely upward, and consumers line the streets taking well branded poison while flaunting cloned individuality.
Each one chasing empty dreams confined by the boundaries the matrix, each one profoundly helpless&lt;!-- secretly wallowing in an sense of profound helplessness--&gt;. Only the most misconceived ego may prosper. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="mental-conditioning"&gt;Mental Conditioning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the time of our birth we are conditioned with a sense of duality that is the foundation of the matrix, and the fundamental disconnect from true existence. Our parents, politicians, language, education, economy, even ourselves, and indeed the system as a whole, are all guilty. Everything is labeled; he is “smart”, she is “dumb”, that is “good” or “bad”. We are taught to aspire to the attainment of wealth and title in a system that’s redundant for the evolving consciousness. This is perfect for the people who run the world because they can go about their business unhindered, while we’re inexorably embroiled in our own self fulfilling prophecies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
busy chasing our tails 
, to validate our actions in the eyes of other's scrutiny.

This is the way it's been set up for us. Our society, notably the economy, has us geared up to chase our own tails in a self fulfilling prophecy until we die. 

for this world of misconception. 
We are conditioned
causes a fundamental disconnect between the 
Our mind is filled concepts of duality and we are raised with a sense of duality 
superfluous 
with superfluous distractions which breeds contempt and duality
segregated 
--&gt;

&lt;!--
, (poverty ghetto),  filled with a sense of their own self importance
Skyscrapers line the skyways as

Towers line the skyways, standing almost as tall as the men in suits housed within.
 --&gt;

&lt;h2 id="awakening"&gt;Awakening&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awakening refers to the attainment of a state of consciousness &lt;!--by an individual or collective--&gt; that’s &lt;!--unfettered by--&gt;free from preconception and manipulation. The process is roughly as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Awareness&lt;/strong&gt;: One begins to glimpse the reality behind the veil.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commitment&lt;/strong&gt;: A commitment is made to living consciously. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Awakening&lt;/strong&gt;: Consciousness shifts and the mind awakens. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;: The only path for an awakened mind is a &lt;a href=""&gt;life of purpose&lt;/a&gt;. Very few people on the planet live like this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True awakening is more than just understanding the framework of lies that surrounds us, it’s about reprogramming the mind and body to be free and &lt;!--protected against--&gt;immune to it’s contagion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the stage of incipient metamorphosis it can be nearly impossible to see the causality of our actions, and people have a tendency of becoming raving “conspiracy theorists”. This doesn’t help anyone, and it only serves to strengthen resistance to change&lt;!--, and the position of the opposition--&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To attempt to “awaken” someone whose psychological construct is totally dependent on the matrix of misconception is bound to have unpredictable consequences, kind of like trying to push 10,000v through a speaker cable. Therefore, people need to be have some kind of inherent structure in place, an alternative to replace the matrix when it collapses. This structure can be localised to the individual or a network of awakened individuals who can provide fortification. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article is a work in progress. Keep reading &lt;a href=""&gt;Living for Purpose&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Forum Government</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://avidsense.com/forum-government/"/>
    <id>http://avidsense.com/forum-government/</id>
    <published>2015-02-09T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-02-17T13:54:22+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="sidebar-section toc"&gt;
  &lt;h4 class="no_toc" id="contents"&gt;Contents&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul id="markdown-toc"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#back-to-basics"&gt;Back to Basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#the-nature-of-the-beast"&gt;The Nature of the Beast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#the-2080-rule"&gt;The 20%/80% Rule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#our-only-chance"&gt;Our Only Chance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humanity now confronts a range of unprecedented problems including pollution of land, sea and air, climate change and developing shortages of fuel, food and water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we collectively grapple with these issues with all the finesse of a drunken sailor, it might just behoove us to go back to first principles and analyse why we struggle with them and what a rational species might do under these circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite simply, we struggle because we are selfish and incapable of making decisions for the greater good. Because of this multi-faceted selfishness, we could very easily render our planet uninhabitable during this century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this score, the new age movement and fundamentalist Christians share some common ground. The new age movement looks to the ancient Mayan calendar and December 2012 as the end of an age, while millions of Christians believe we are in the end-times, with Armageddon a few short years away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However it is not just these spiritual and religious groups that believe our way of living must come to an end. It is a belief commonly held by a significant proportion, if not a majority of socially aware people around the globe, that our current situation is hopeless and that some sort of cataclysm is necessary if we are to birth a new and better reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The irony is that world-wide we have millions of highly intelligent people with brilliant ideas that have the potential to create a wonderful new paradigm in every facet of our lives. These same people almost invariably feel disenfranchised and apathetic, while a tiny minority controlled by vested interests drives us further into the mire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we are to survive, let alone prosper, we must now develop new, more intelligent ways of governing ourselves, so that we learn to harness and benefit from this phenomenal resource. Our only hope now is to learn how to objectively develop policies that are based on the best of our combined thought processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="back-to-basics"&gt;Back to Basics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The justification for this is simple. If there were 100 of us left on Earth, huddled up in a cave, pondering our future, would we want to elect and pay someone to do our thinking for us, or would we want to hold a facilitated meeting that would synergise the best of our ideas? Not much of a choice, is it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forum Government is a new concept and consequently not much thought has gone into it. &lt;!-- (Let’s give full marks to the Australian Prime Minister, Mr. Rudd for at least acknowledging the relevance of community involvement at the national level.) --&gt; In practice, it requires an objective evaluation process according to a set of predetermined core values. These values should reflect our highest potential and could include, for example, innovation, empowerment, open co-operation, self-sufficiency and sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each submitted idea or variation of an idea is rated by a panel of qualified experts, with each government portfolio having it’s own panel. Governments are elected on the basis of the core values they espouse, rather than the promises they make, the difference being that there is no longer a direct connection between politician and outcome. That equates with less scope for corruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With computers we have the potential to implement Forum Government. Certainly we need to develop the software to make it fair, workable and incorruptible, however once the Bill Gates’ of our world set their minds to it, it will quickly become practicable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we must insist on it, in the knowledge that it is ultimately irresistible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-nature-of-the-beast"&gt;The Nature of the Beast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all our recent technological advancements, we humans are a pretty pathetic bunch. We have promoted ourselves to our level of incompetency and are quite simply unfit to be in control of this planet. This is what so many of us know in our heart of hearts. It’s not that we’re all rotten, it just that the way we govern ourselves belongs in the dark ages and it’s hard to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humanity is capable of supreme altruism, heroism and concerted action, especially when all else has failed. There can be little doubt that those qualities will kick in when we reach that stage. Though we are probably there right now, the pain is not yet great enough. Denial prevails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our current world situation, it is difficult to know what that stage looks like. My guess is we’ll need to endure the suffering of the loss of a significant % of the population. Impoverishment of the wealthy is another criterion and we’re going down that road right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there is an intermediate stage we must pass through before crying enough and stepping into our inherent greatness. That is the stage of the one world government, the pinnacle of globalization and all the other dehumanizing polices that are turning our world into a soup kitchen with insufficient soup. Rest assured, the blueprint of the ultimate prize is waiting in the wings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-2080-rule"&gt;The 20%/80% Rule&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humanity is controlled though fear. Just as a small child instinctively knows how to manipulate it’s parents, so do our political leaders know they can persuade us to follow a course of action by making us afraid of the consequences of it’s alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are those whose intellect allows them to transcend that to a greater or lesser extent, however they are a distinct minority, say, 20%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we have a bizarre situation in which the “will” of the “unthinking” 80% can be easily manipulated to swamp the superior thinking of the 20%, implementing policies and agendas that serve only a powerful few, who are beholding to their peers, with little regard for the opinions of the masses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;History is replete with examples of nations unjustly waging war on other nations, supported by a majority which has been made afraid of the consequences of not doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is obvious and anyone reading this article will know it to be true. It is the nature of things on planetarium Earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is why democracy must now die… &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="our-only-chance"&gt;Our Only Chance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tiny window of opportunity exists for us to turn our future around. We have the opportunity, right now, to investigate and develop the mechanisms that will enable to shrug off our sense of fear, apathy and doom; the very mechanisms that we will need when we reach the critical stage outlined above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forum government can’t and won’t happen now. The death throes of the old, tried and false have just begun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is a lot of work to be done developing computer models for objective policy making, based on diverse inputs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For there will surely soon come a time when the metaphorical 100 will need them.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Surviving the Collapse</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://avidsense.com/surviving-the-collapse/"/>
    <id>http://avidsense.com/surviving-the-collapse/</id>
    <published>2015-02-05T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-02-09T12:09:17+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Luo Bing</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;!--
TODO
* expand What to Expect with points
--&gt;

&lt;div class="sidebar-section toc"&gt;
  &lt;h4 class="no_toc" id="contents"&gt;Contents&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul id="markdown-toc"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-to-expect"&gt;What to Expect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#preparedness"&gt;Preparedness&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#tools-and-equipment"&gt;Tools and Equipment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#food-supply"&gt;Food Supply&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#location-and-shelter"&gt;Location and Shelter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A battle rages between the people and the powers that be, and the steaks are our very freedom and human dignity. We live at a crucial turning point in mankind’s history, and the outlook is grim but not hopeless. Apathy and cynicism are the new swag, and every subversive move made by the encroaching dark hand of control is passed off under the guise of utilitarian action&lt;!-- masked as a utilitarian ethics --&gt;, but one must never doubt the resilience of the human spirit when faced with true adversity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This intent of this article is not to spread fear and panic, rather to provide a parctical reference to surviving the climactic state of affairs faced by the new generation. Lets face it, the people who run the show would do ANYTHING to maintain the balance of power, and the world can only hope that YOU feel as passionately about your freedoms as they do about control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Our fragile society is comprised of so many complex moving parts, which at any point could come crumbling down around our ears. Very few people are ready for such an occurrence, and it's both frightening and necessary to understand that at any given moment we are only three square meals away from total anarchy.
--&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what-to-expect"&gt;What to Expect&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A total collapse could be triggered may be triggered by a multitude of various events, such as a financial crisis (such as what’s currently unfolding in both America and Europe), an external trade shock, an adverse supply shock or the bursting of an economic bubble, and may be also brought about suddenly by way of a natural disaster or epidemic (Ebola comes to mind). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However we happen to arrive there, the results are the same, social chaos, civil unrest, a breakdown of law and order, and in the event of a catastrophic hard collapse, military intervention and the emrgence of a new &lt;a href=""&gt;NWO&lt;/a&gt; type totalitarian reigime enforcing martial law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
 and order resulting in anarchy. (examples)
 
A pessimistic scenario of future events includes a banking crisis  leading to hyperinflation and a collapse of the economy.

This is the way our [capitalist economy is geared](), so when the current economy is abolished wealth will be resynchronised with those holding all the power, and the cycle can continue as they see fit.
--&gt;

&lt;h2 id="preparedness"&gt;Preparedness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the event of a total collapse the skills deemed important in our modern world will cease to be relevant. Practical survival skills will be essential, and a certain level of preparedness will be a massive advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask yourself, what would you do if the grid stopped functioning?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where would you get food?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where would you go?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How would you be self-sufficient?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How would you protect yourself and your loved ones?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you have the practical skills to rebuild after a collapse?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you answered even one of those questions in the positive, then you’re doing better than most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One should have a working knowledge of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your local geography&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Natural food sources&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Food storage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Water collection (?)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Starting a fire&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Building a basic shelter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Martial self-defence including firearms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to learn these skills is to disappear into the wilderness, pitting man against nature for a few days. Take a list and the beare necessities with you, and make mistakes until you get it right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of preparedness one should have all the tools necessary for survival, food supply, and somewhere safe to go in the event of disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="tools-and-equipment"&gt;Tools and Equipment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming soon …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="food-supply"&gt;Food Supply&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming soon …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="location-and-shelter"&gt;Location and Shelter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming soon …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
This is how you control society. Keep the masses dumb and poorly educated, make sure that people have low paying jobs that require them to live pay check to pay check, and then feed them mindless drivel as news to keep their minds off of real issues. Because it's hard for society to organize and fight tyranny when each day is a struggle to eat.


Int he case of a total system collapse, on of the first things to stop will be supermarket deliveries. In Australia ... trade agreements ...
Three square emans from anarchy ...

Store enough food for your immediate group to survive for a minimum of three months. Brown rice(storage, survival suration?) is a safe bet, as well as long life canned food and astronout/army meals. Also keep some salt, and a water filter with enough replacable elements to keep you out of trouble.

You won'twant to live on rice forever, so your aim will be to setup, or have access to, a garden as soon as possible.

It's a good idea to keep enough seeds to start a garden of your own, or if you get caught out then find a produce farm as soon as possible ad offer your servbices. Farm will fast become the most important places on the planet, and will be in need of extra staff to meet the extra demand, and security from looters.

## Equipment

Bug-out 101

## Location

For most first world countries the government has disaster reaction plans in place (take from Food...)
--&gt;

&lt;!--
In the event of collapse the skills that deemed important in our modern world will cease to be relevant, and set of survival skills and preparedness will be required. 

a much more practical 

It is therefore prudent to be prepared and educate yourself in the event that such disasters may come to pass. 

More to come soon ...
--&gt;

&lt;!--
## What Does It Look Like?

A pessimistic scenario of future events includes a banking crisis, followed by a
government bailout and the eventual nationali­zation of all banks. The
final cost is staggering and is paid with money created by the Federal Reserve.
It is passed on to the public in the form of inflation.

Further inflation is caused by the continual expansion of welfare programs, socialized
medicine, entitlement programs, and interest on the national debt. The dollar is finally
abandoned as the de facto currency of the world. Trillions of dollars are
sent back to the United States by foreign investors to be converted as
quickly as possible into tangible assets. That causes even greater
inflation than before. So massive is the inflationary pressure that
industry and commerce come to a halt. Barter becomes the means of
exchange. America takes her place among the depressed nations of
South America, Africa, and Asia—mired together in economic equality.

domestic violence, 

, a new global currency, the arrival of U.N. "Peacekeeping" forces, and a new totalitarian regime enforcing high-tech feudalism.


We have already seen recent
--&gt;
&lt;!--
But this time, the programs begin to take on an international flavor. The American dollar is replaced by a new UN money, and the Federal Reserve System becomes a branch operation of the IMF/World Bank.
--&gt;

&lt;!--
Politicians seize upon the opportunity and offer bold reforms. The reforms are more of exactly what caused the problem in the first place: expanded governmental power, new regulatory agencies, and more restrictions on freedom. 

The failed currency will be replaced a new one designed so that electronic transfers will gradually replace cash and checking accounts. This permits government agencies to monitor the financial activities of every person. A machine-readable ID card is used for that purpose. If an individual is red flagged by any government agency, the card does not clear, and he is cut off from all economic transactions and travel. It is the ultimate control.

Increasing violence in the streets from revolutionary movements and ethnic clashes provide the government with an excuse for martial law. The public is happy to see "Peacekeepers" checking ID cards. The police-state arrives in the name of public safety.

Eventually all private dwellings are taken over by the government as a result of bailing out the home-mortgage industry. Rental property is also taken, as former landlords are unable to pay property taxes. People are allowed to live in these dwellings at reasonable cost, or no cost at all. It gradually becomes clear, however, that the government is now the owner of all homes and apartments. People are living in them only at the pleasure of the government. They can be reassigned at any time.

Wages and prices are controlled. Dissidents are placed into work armies. There are no more autos except for the ruling elite. Public transportation is provided for the masses, and those with limited skills live in government housing within walking distance of their assigned jobs. Men have been reduced to the level of serfs who are subservient to their masters. Their condition of life can only be described as high-tech feudalism.
--&gt;

&lt;!--
There is no certainty that the future will unfold in exactly that manner, because there are too many variables. For example, if we had assumed that there will not be a banking crisis, then our journey would be different. We would not see long lines of depositors or panic-buying in the stores or closing of the stock market. But we would still witness the same scenes of despair in the more distant future. We merely would have traveled a different path of events to get there. That is because the forces driving our society into global totalitarianism would not have changed one iota. We still would have the doomsday mechanisms at work. We would have the CFR in control of the power centers of government and the media. We would have an electorate which is unaware of what is being done to them and, therefore, unable to resist. Through environmental and economic treaties and through military disarmament to the UN, we would witness the same emergence of a world central bank, a world government, and a world army to, enforce its dictates. Inflation and wage/price controls would have progressed more or less the same, driving consumer goods out of existence and mmen into bondage. Instead of moving toward The New World Order in a series of economic spasms, we merely would have traveled a less violent path and arrived at exactly the same destination.
--&gt;

&lt;!--
* **Travel Restrictions** This will begin with restrictions on foreign travel, including suspension/removal of passports. (This has begun in a small way in both the EU and US.) Later, travel restrictions will be extended within the boundaries of countries (highway checkpoints, etc.)

* **Confiscation of wealth** The EU has instituted the confiscation of bank accounts, which can be expected to become an international form of governmental theft. This does not automatically mean that other assets, such as precious metals and real estate will also be confiscated, but it does mean that the barrier for confiscation has been eliminated. There is therefore no reason to assume that any asset is safe from any government that approves theft through bail-ins.

* **Food Shortages** The food industry operates on very small profit margins and survives only as a result of quick payment of invoices. With dramatic inflation, marginal businesses (suppliers, wholesalers, and retailers) will fall by the wayside. The percentage of failing businesses will be dependent upon the duration and severity of the inflationary trend.

* **Squatters Rebellions** A dramatic increase in the number of home and business foreclosures will result in homelessness for anyone whose debt exceeds his ability to pay—even those who presently appear to be well-off. As numbers rise significantly, a new homeless class will be created amongst the former middle class. As they become more numerous, large scale ownership of property may give way to large scale “possession” of property.

* **Riots** These will likely happen spontaneously due to the above conditions, but if not, governments will create them to justify their desire for greater control of the masses.

* **Martial Law** Martial Law and may be initially termed as EPP (Emergency Police Protection). The US has already prepared for this, with the passing of the 2012 National Defense Authorization Act (NDAA), which many interpret as declaring the US to be a “battlefield.” The NDAA allows the suspension of habeas corpus, indefinite detention, and the assumption that any resident may be considered an enemy combatant. Similar legislation may be expected in other countries that perceive martial law as a solution to civil unrest.


## Preparedness
--&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Economic Entropy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://avidsense.com/economic-entrophy-decline-and-collapse/"/>
    <id>http://avidsense.com/economic-entrophy-decline-and-collapse/</id>
    <published>2015-02-03T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-02-09T13:04:39+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Luo Bing</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="sidebar-section toc"&gt;
  &lt;h4 class="no_toc" id="contents"&gt;Contents&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul id="markdown-toc"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#fractional-reserve-banking"&gt;Fractional Reserve Banking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#business-cycles"&gt;Business Cycles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#fixing-the-numbers"&gt;Fixing the Numbers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#the-new-generation"&gt;The New Generation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#stages-of-decline"&gt;Stages of Decline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#total-collapse"&gt;Total Collapse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!--
TODO:
- Effects at a governmental level

TERMS:
* quantitative easing
* dances with debt
* federal budget
* forex
* what happens in a default?
* hyperinflation 
* unemployment
* civil unrest
* negative gearing
* european union

REFS:
* http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Economic_collapse
* http://www.targetofopportunity.com/5_stages.htm
* http://theeconomiccollapseblog.com/archives/24-reasons-why-millennials-are-screaming-mad-about-our-unfair-economy
* http://thedailybell.com/definitions/params/id/634/
* http://thedailybell.com/definitions/params/id/2958/

The Federal Reserve has been made a legalized counterfeiting operation and the member banks along with The Treasury and the Wall Street banksters have been made a legalized money laundering operation who support the federal crime syndicate while financing the campaigns of "our" elected office holders. The entire legalized illicit enterprise is founded on a terminal case of stupidity.

Insolvency actually is inherent in the system itself, a
system called fractional reserve banking. The Federal Reserve System has
legalized and institutionalized the dishonesty of issuing more hat checks than
there are hats and it has devised complex methods of disguising this practice
as a perfectly proper and normal feature of banking. Students of finance are
told that there simply is no other way for the system to function. Once that
premise is accepted, then all attention can be focused, not on the inherent
fraud, but on ways and means to live with it and make it as painless as
possible. When a bank's bookkeeping assets finally become less than its
liabilities, the rules of the game call for transferring the losses to the
depositors themselves. This means they pay twice: once as taxpayers and again
as depositors. The mechanism by which this is accomplished is called the
Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation. Using the fed to pass these losses on to the depositors through
inflation

What has any of this to do with the Federal Reserve System? The answer is
that the Federal Reserve is the starting point of the pessimistic scenario. The chain of events begins with fiat money created by a central bank, which leads to government debt, which causes inflation, which destroys the economy, which impoverishes the people, which provides an excuse for increasing government power, which is an on-going process culminating in totalitarianism. Eliminate the Federal Reserve from this equation, and the pessimis­tic scenario ceases to exist. That is the seventh and final reason to abolish the Fed: It is an instrument of totalitarianism.

If the optimistic scenario is too optimistic and the pessimistic scenario is too pessimistic, then what is the scenario that we should hope lies in our future?

There is a middle course that lies between optimism and pessimism. It is
called realism. Calling it a realistic scenario is not meant to imply that it is
predetermined to happen, nor that it is even likely to happen. It is realistic
only in the sense that it can happen if certain conditions are met.

Let us begin by allowing our opponent, Cynicism, to state the problem we face: "Is it realistic to believe that the current trends can actually be reversed? Isn't it just fantasy to think that anything can be done at this late date to break
the CFR's hold over government, media, and education? Do we really expect the gum-chewing public to go upstream against the indoctrination of newspapers,
magazines, television, and movies?"

Apathy joins in: "Forget it. There's nothing you can do. The bankers and politicians have all the money and all the power. The game is already over. Make the most of it, and enjoy life while you can."

Do not listen to Cynicism and Apathy.

They are agents of your enemy. They want you to quietly get in line and submit
without a struggle. However, they do make a point that must not be overlooked. The battle has progressed far, and our position is not good. If we are to reverse the present trends, we must be prepared to make a herculean effort. That does
not mean "Write your Congressman" or "Vote on Tuesday" or "Sign a
petition" or "Send in a donation." That is far too easy. Those measures still play an
important role in the battle plan but they fall far short of the need. Armchair campaigns will no longer do it.

Before turning to the question of what kind of effort will be required, let us
first become clear on what it is we want to accomplish.
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When speaking about the modern capitalist economic model, the phrase “broken by design” comes to mind. Decline is inherent in it’s very design; debt is inevitably incurred or created, more money is injected into the economy, and inflation creeps in to devalue people’s hard earned wealth. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This fiasco continues until such time as the system becomes insolvent and comes crashing down, then it’s rinse and repeat. The idea that money is actually worth something is purely illusory, and while there was once a &lt;a href=""&gt;gold standard&lt;/a&gt;, now money is just symbolic of the banks blatant corruption, and the ineptitude of civil libertarians to do anything about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“But why on earth would anyone design it that way?”, asks the innocent child.&lt;br /&gt;
“It’s about balance of power and maintaining control, my precioussss”, replies the small clammy reptilian looking figure.&lt;br /&gt;
The small clammy figure pulls a balloon from his pocket and proceeds to inflate it, and the child sits mesmerised as the big shiny balloon inflates before his eyes.&lt;br /&gt;
The small clammy figure continues to inflate the balloon, when will of a sudden, BANG!! The balloon explodes from too much air. The child bursts into tears with outstretched arms, and the small clammy figure smiles a twisted smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more about &lt;a href="#fractional-reserve-banking"&gt;Fractional Reserve Banking&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="#business-cycles"&gt;Business Cycles&lt;/a&gt; to find out how this process is manipulated by the banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="fractional-reserve-banking"&gt;Fractional Reserve Banking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially, fractional-reserve banking means banks can legally issue more hat checks than there are hats. As defined by Wikipedia:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Fractional-reserve banking is the practice whereby a bank holds reserves (to satisfy demands for withdrawals) that are less than the amount of its customers’ deposits. Reserves are held at the bank as currency, or as deposits in the bank’s accounts at the central bank. Because bank deposits are usually considered money in their own right, fractional-reserve banking permits the money supply to grow beyond the amount of the underlying reserves of base money originally created by the central bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what happens when everyone comes to collect and their aren’t enough hats? Therein lies the problem. Let’s illustrate the issue with a practical situation: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mr Bean enters the bank to secure a $50000 home loan, with his house as collateral of course. The bank accepts the load, and gives Mr Bean his money with an interest of $5000. Mr Bean is over the moon and goes on his merry way, but what Mr Bean doesn’t know is that the money he has just been given does not actually equate to deposits held by the bank, or at the central bank (in the time of the gold standard it would have been exchangeable for gold and silver)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unfortunately for Mr Bean he has a bad gambling problem, and he blows most of his money on the horses … and the rest on a costly divorce settlement. Unable to make his repayments, poor old Mr Bean declares bankruptcy, and the bank takes his house. Mr Bean is really up shit creek, but the bank is laughing because they’ve just scored another house.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mr Bean’s bookie on the other hand is living it up on a yaght spending cash hand over fist, which is great for the economy because for intents and purposes it looks like “boom times”, especially at the strip club he frequents.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The reality is though, that a whole bunch of debt has been created at the central bank, and will now be generously passed on to the populace as inflation. Now Mr Bean can’t even afford a cardboard box to sleep under, and little Mr Bean Jr. (whom his missus had with her new husband) who just graduated from business school is flipping burgers at Mc Donalds.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Even is Mr Bean had gotten his shit together and paid back the loan, the Bank would be richer, so for the middle-man ie. the commercial bank, it’s a win-win situation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations if you made it all the way through that! Hopefully it can be seen then that a fractional reserve system is inherently unstable and fraudulent, and at odds with underlying real physical variables. The money issued as loans on principle is truly created from nothing and backed up by nothing, and this is indeed the very definition of counterfeited money: &lt;em&gt;Money created from nothing and backed up by nothing&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such a system is designed operate in temporary cycles of artificial activity, until such a time as there is an inevitable day of reckoning wherein the system collapses onto itself, wiping away all fraudulent claims and re-synchronising wealth with its true owners. Money is destroyed, and the true order of affairs is re-established once more. See &lt;a href="#business-cycles"&gt;Business Cycles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="business-cycles"&gt;Business Cycles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The business cycle, as defined in the modern day, is a primarily central bank-driven phenomenon. The Wikipedia definition does not really do it justice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The business cycle is the downward and upward movement of levels of gross domestic product (GDP) and refers to the period of expansions and contractions in the level of economic activities (business fluctuations) around its long-term growth trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central bank prints more money, injecting more credit than is necessary into the economy. The volume of money fools investors into thinking that a rapid expansion is underway, which, in turn stimulates a “boom”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the economy overheats, products and services that are an unnecessary outcome of the artificial boom become commonplace, leading to glut and, inevitably, to a collapse. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the boom, the central bank may artificially increase interest rates while also raising the amount of money available via credit and its printing plants. This inflation eases the economy (best case) into a “soft landing” – after which the cycle begins again. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="fixing-the-numbers"&gt;Fixing the Numbers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!--
All capitalist economies at some point experience the inevitable decay of economic decline, its inherent in their design. 

The slippery descent of economic decline usually begins as a result of widespread corruption or mismanagement of funds within the government and banking systems, sometimes even with deliberate intent. The unfortunate fallout is felt most keenly by members of the proletariat who live from week to week on a paycheck, and rely on the wellbeing of the economy for employment and to keep interest rates and inflation minimal. [1] 

It's the task of economists working for these very same government agencies to make the economy look strong on paper, as it aids their government's agenda by bolstering public opinion and reflecting positively on the success of their policies and reforms.

While the world governments desperately play the forex in a bid to keep the outlook looking peachy from the outside in, 

It's the task of government economists to make the economy look strong on paper, as it aids their government's agenda by bolstering public opinion and reflecting positively on the success of their policies and reforms. 

In light of the statistical slights-of-hand employed by the government to doctor figures, it's necessary to seek alternative sources of information and statistics to properly gauge the actual state of the economy, such as:
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With world governments desperately playing the &lt;a href=""&gt;forex&lt;/a&gt;, and government economists employing statistical slight-of-hand to keep the economic outlook looking peachy from the outside in, &lt;!-- and bolster public opinion and reflecting positively on the success of their policies and reforms, --&gt;figures on a sheet of paper can’t always be taken at face value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s necessary to seek multiple sources of information to properly gauge the actual state of an economy, such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rate of inflation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Average disposable income compared to cost of living&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interest rates and fluctuation over time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;State of health care and social welfare&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Percentage of university graduates unable to secure work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rate of unemployment among the proletariat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spend some time living among the proletariat!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-new-generation"&gt;The New Generation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dangerous times lie ahead, and the issue is social. A large portion of the youth of today (millennials) are growing up in a state of total disillusionment and disempowerment. While this may be nothing new, the odds and stakes are higher than they ever were before. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the most part, children of the previous generation grew up with strong morals values instilled by their family and the society around them. Small business owners took pride in their work, people exchanged and bartered at markets, cared for each other, and life was good. These days we have mass corporitisation and poverty breeding contempt and hate for the world in young minds, and thanks to modern technology and communications the perception of this reality is no longer isolated to the individual or the immediate community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s small wonder young people turn away from the world and immerse themselves in technology, passive entertainments and destructive behaviour. After all, what is there to look forward too? A crappy minimum wage job and a crippling mortgage in 10 years time? Please, young people need something to believe in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apathy is our worst enemy - people who don’t care about anything are easily controlled and coerced. One can only hope the youngsters of the new generation wake up before all their freedoms have been systematically revoked and they are too blind to see or do anything about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="stages-of-decline"&gt;Stages of Decline&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process of economic decay is roughly as follows: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In a strong economy everyone lives in abundance, goods are readily available, and life is good. People become accustomed to the good life, and complacency and a sense of entitlement sets in. Inflation and decline can caused by a number of practical reasons, including and not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fractional reserve banking loan debt (American fiasco)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Central bank generating surplus credit (Business Cycle)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Rising oil prices (peak oil scare and corruption)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Rising real-estate prices&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Government contract corruption (Philippines, china ghost cities)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Abuse of social welfare programs (Australia)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Increased supply over demand&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Unions demanding wage increases&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Market bubbles&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The economy is sent into a steady decline as inflation rises. Unemployment is on the rise. Ever increasing numbers of people receive government assistance in one form or another. Government spending has increased dramatically. The price of gold, silver, and other precious metals reach record highs.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Prolonged periods of decay trigger a recession, causing businesses to fail and leaving a large portion of the population jobless and homeless. Infrastructure begins to decay due to reprioritisation and lack of government funds. It’s do or die for the working class, and large scale civil unrest and riots become the norm.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;At this point the economic collapse can be sent into overdrive, when the people fearing banks will become insolvent, panic and withdraw their deposits en masse causing a “bank run”. As a bank run progresses, it generates its own kind of momentum, with the likelihood of default increasing as more people withdraw their deposits. This can destabilize a bank to the point of facing sudden bankruptcy. At this point a bank must either default (great depression, 10c on the dollar), or be bailed out (American bank bailout).
&lt;!--
 The common practice is for the government to "borrow" money to compensate for the financial crisis, incurring further debt and political inter-dependency (see the political assassin doco for more info).
--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the event of a total collapse, infrastructure grinds to a complete halt and there are no more deliveries to fill the supermarket shelves. There is a rush for supplies and everything goes within in a matter of hours. The power grid becomes unstable and rolling blackouts are a daily occurrence. Those who have hoarded goods or gasoline now offer them at exorbitant prices, and those who can’t afford them turn to vandalism and violence in order to survive.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Total lawlessness ensues and urban areas become war zones controlled by gangs. Severe poverty and starvation become a common sight. The government implements martial law and now controls the supply and distribution of food and water. Clashes break out between civilian militia and government forces. Those who have no means of providing for themselves have no choice but to accept the government’s totalitarian regime. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id="total-collapse"&gt;Total Collapse&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term “economic collapse” has been used to describe a broad range of bad economic conditions, ranging from a severe, prolonged depression with high bankruptcy rates and high unemployment (such as the Great Depression of the 1930s), to a breakdown in normal commerce caused by hyperinflation (such as in Weimar Germany in the 1920s), or even an economically caused sharp increase in the death rate and perhaps even a decline in population (such as in countries of the former USSR in the 1990s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further reading on preparing yourself for such an event read &lt;a href="/surviving-the-collapse"&gt;Surviving the Collapse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Engineering the Mind</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://avidsense.com/engineering-the-mind/"/>
    <id>http://avidsense.com/engineering-the-mind/</id>
    <published>2014-07-05T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-08-15T04:45:04+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kam Low</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;!--
banner: /engineering-the-mind/xiao-feng-dmt-1024x680.jpg


- read about mind hacking
- storing information (improving memory)
- STRENGTHEINING MIND AND BODY TOGETHER
	- strengthening feedback loops and synapses through focused training.
--&gt;

&lt;div class="sidebar-section toc"&gt;
  &lt;h4 class="no_toc" id="contents"&gt;Contents&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul id="markdown-toc"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#paradoxical-thinking"&gt;Paradoxical Thinking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#true-intelligence"&gt;True Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#wu-gong-masters"&gt;Wu-Gong Masters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#recognising-and-reprogramming-patterns"&gt;Recognising and Reprogramming Patterns&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#visualise"&gt;Visualise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#accept"&gt;Accept&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#override"&gt;Override&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mind is a tricky mistress, but it’s our mistress, and with the proper focused training it can be taught to function and create beyond our wildest dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like in most fields that push the boundaries of fringe science, our knowledge neuroscience is limited; we don’t know how the really brain functions and stores information yet, but we do know how to program it for a higher level of efficiency. Wouldn’t it be a shame if the crazy super-computer that sits in your head wasn’t able to shine because you didn’t learn the proper commands?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mind and body that understands the underlying principles of nature can apply them to great effect in learning, thinking and application. The education system hasn’t done much for us in this regard, tending to cram our minds full of facts and figures, rather than teaching it about system, technique and strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not a psychologist or a neuroscientist, just a humble programmer and martial artist, and as such my information will not be presented in the standard academic format. However, I’ve worked hard to sharpen my skills over the years, and am now having a great time working with some of the top companies in the world - so glean from this article what you will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
 who's spent the last 15 years developing my skills, and is now working with some of the top companies in the world.
--&gt;

&lt;!--
The mind processes information visually in the language of forms and shapes[], but the perception and meaning of this language is governed by conscious and unconscious patterns. Physicists, alchemists, philosophers and mathematicians, and more, all attempt to explain nature by reducing it into more understandable and manageable data sets. The good news is you don't need a fancy degree, just strong will and a perceptive mind.
--&gt;

&lt;h3 id="paradoxical-thinking"&gt;Paradoxical Thinking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paradoxical thinking is an important element of learning that challenges us to look beyond the bounds of what is considered rational and therefore ‘valid’. Paradoxically, paradoxical arguments are generally considered to be ‘invalid’, but the value of the paradox lies not it it’s validity, it’s in the resulting journey of the mind that’s given rise to by &lt;!--the reconciliation of--&gt; conflicting arguments. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
- yin yang and paradoxes
	- for most ideas that are considered to be true, there are generally polar opposites that are also considered to be true. This forms the basis 'Yin Yang', the Chinese belief that states that everything in nature has an opposite, otherwise it could not exist in the first place.

Masters of their destiny will tell you that the human animal thrives under genuine adversity, with the constant guidance of the internal voice of opposition.
If the minds ability to question 
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Darwinism teaches us that an organism requires adversity in order to thrive or evolve into a stronger version of itself. Take a look at our own history - nothing great has ever been achieved without a significant measure of conflict and adversity. Therefore, think of the paradox is the equivalent of fighting a war in the mind. Without regular battle we all know the troops become restless and complacent, and the last thing you want is for your troops to turn to the booze and brothels - unless you so will it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While paradoxical thinking plays an important role in helping you to ask the right questions, it’s also a trap in it’s own right. The problem with “thinking”, is that the mind ends up getting caught up in an endless iteration, with no hope of a resolution until the scope changes and more data becomes available and or accessible. Since most of our actual processing happens at a subconscious level, we don’t have as much control over the process as we would like. This is why you just can’t remember the name of that gorgeous actress when you want to, and the name always pops into your head a minute later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many computers programs, the brain uses multiple threads and to defer long running intensive tasks. This means that once you’ve fed your brain the correct information, it’s time to take a step back and let it do what it does best. There’s no point in rushing - you’d be better off sticking 10,000v wires in your ear and hoping that it made you smarter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avoid lazyness too. It’s hard with all this awesome technology I know, but the mind that becomes complacent forgets how to visit the extremes, and the internal voice that desires knowledge and action becomes nothing more than the whisper of self-loathing that drives self-destructive tendencies, and is eventually lost altogether. 
&lt;!-- 
	Trying to shortcut the process is as futile
	as trying to break the natural laws, but we can use stronger laws to overcome weaker laws to optimise the result. 
 which is the ability to see directly to the heart of things
--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paradoxical thinking is only a way of thinking, and a step on the path to true intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="true-intelligence"&gt;True Intelligence&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True intelligence is the ability to see directly to the heart of things, either by way of empirical knowledge, or some unexplained primordial intuition&lt;!--[]--&gt;. Questions are often raised as to weather our knowledge is self-contained, or if we are connected to some other combined or cloud consciousness, but theyre purely speculative. For the purpose of thios article we’ll just assume that knowledge is learned, and that anything else is outside of our direct control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many forms of intelligence, academic, intuitive, emotional and so on, but it’s the combination of all these forms of intelligence that affords us the “insight” and “wisdom” to tackle the really big problems. Our current society and education system is geared up so that only the academic subset is of any real value, and everything else is largely superfluous. Hopefully you don’t believe that to be true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Einstein’s genius was attributed to his ability to perceive the heart of things with a childlike sincerity. While everyone else was explaining themselves in circles with complex equations, Einstein’s discoveries were so black and white that everyone hit themselves on the head asking “why the hell didn’t I think of that?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the heart of true inteligence is objective perception. Imagine you’re a baby taking your first steps; how vivid and present the experience must be. For children there’s no layers between what’s happening and what’s experienced. For most of us though, our psyche is so marred with unconscious patterning and coping mechanisms, that by the time we reach adulthood the ability to be truly present in the moment is a distant memory. The irony here is that when the mind reaches this stage, becoming more intelligent is actually more of an unlearning or an unravelling process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True intelligence is dependent on more that just our perception though; equally important is the ability to process information and act accordingly in the moment. While these skills come more naturally for some, they are available to all by following a path of mastery that incorporates the mind, body and spirit, and constant testing of limitations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
So what does it mean to see to the "heat of things"? 

 far from it, it's to say that  
, which is necessary for perception
where the adult mind tends to analyse and rationalise itself around in circles. In this respect, our mind is it's own worst enemy.

Over time something changes; the mind develops comping mechanisms and patterns that filter stimulus and affect the way we process information. we become desensitised and dull.

A quality that's recognises in children (and also Einstein), is their ability to perceive the heart of the situation. 

Einstein's genius during his time was his ability to perceive the heart of things with a childlike sincerity. 
There was no layers to cloud his perception
--&gt;

&lt;!--
Most of the information in the brain is stored in the subconscious, whch is always processing, this can't happen until the conscious mind takes a break. 

, and that's something that can't happen when the mind is on endless iteration. 

Every day we are bombarded with an insane amount of stimulus, and if we were consciously aware of it all at once, the we would surely go insane! The mind conveniently develops coping mechanisms that filter and sometimes modify non-critical and overly traumatic details and experiences. While these mechanisms are necessary, the process of desensitisation can dull the mind over time.

An intelligent and active mind is defined by it's ability to see directly to the core of the matter; either by way of empirical knowledge, or some unexplained primordial intuition[]. For now we'll assume that knowledge is learned, and that anything else is outside of our direct control, therefore outside the scope of this article.


So how does one stay sane in a world full of contradictions and paradoxes?

Physicists, alchemists, philosophers and mathematicians, and more, all attempt to explain nature by reducing it into more understandable and manageable data sets. The good news is you don't need a fancy degree, just strong will and a perceptive mind.

Every day we are bombarded with an insane amount of stimulus, and if we were consciously aware of it all at once, the we would surely go insane! The mind conveniently develops coping mechanisms that filter and sometimes modify non-critical and overly traumatic details and experiences. While these mechanisms are necessary, the process of desensitisation can dull the mind over time.

An intelligent and active mind is defined by it's ability to see directly to the core of the matter; either by way of empirical knowledge, or some unexplained primordial intuition[]. For now we'll assume that knowledge is learned, and that anything else is outside of our direct control, therefore outside the scope of this article.

## Reprogramming Your Mind
The process of dumbing down can be reversed by...
by reprogramming the mind to filter out the 
 We do this by filtering 
 it part by part

 -- wu-gong?
The first thing required is will-power, the will to constantly override the internal voice of opposition which wants to enforce your learned patterns.
Will-power is developed though conflict, be it with the self, others or situational. 
The key to developing will-power, as well as most learned skills, is focus.
--&gt;

&lt;h2 id="wu-gong-masters"&gt;Wu-Gong Masters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gong fu masters are the true masters of reality, for they have connected the mind to the the body in a way that enables them to achieve seemingly super-human feats. These feats may seem improbable and even impossible to most, and I would tend to agree had I not had the privelidge of training with some of the top masters myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In martial arts there are two predominant philosophies; one that favours the hard (external), and one that favours the soft (internal). Internal martial arts that focus on how to maximise force with minimal effort are of particular interest to me, because they show the existence of a commonly misunderstood force that can’t be generated by muscular exertion alone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a “special” force that moves through the human body that can be accessed and demonstrated by a few of the top masters at will. I’m not going to call it “ki”, “qi” or anything else liable to be misinterpreted or accompanied with hallucinations of mystical warriors flying through bamboo forests, rather it’s the kind of condition that allows a mother to lift up a car to rescue her baby&lt;!--[]--&gt;, or a master to project their entire body mass through a small movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Most of us have mapped our neural pathways sufficiently to be able to preform daily functions with ease, but what if your brain was mapped to accelerate and project your entire body mass through any movement? ****

and can be unexpectedly triggered under extreme conditions

, not only is he is one of the great internal gong fu masters, but he has the internal control to cycle his heart rate at will - though all ... pulses measured in Chinese medicine.

facilitates this force transference. The other precondition for 'Lim Tao' to work is
This kind of ability has nothing to do with one's academic intelligence whatsoever. 

is one of the most intelligent people I have ever met, he 

Sigong Chu has the ability to read your energy and intent before you even know what's happening yourself. I don't know about you, but for me that's way cooler than reciting PI to 100,000 places.

Those who spend a lot of time in their mind often neglect their body, but it's only through the combination of mind, body and what we subjectively call spirit, that true intelligence can be attained.These skills though,but they have a much greater potential over short term physical gains.

This is why they take so long, and require a certain type of individual to master them.
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chu Shong Tin is one such master who can demonstrate these abilities. Sigong Chu is a life-long Wing Chun practitioner known as the “King of Siu Lim Tao”, and is one of Yip Man’s oldest and most highly regarded students. Sigong Chu often talks about “Lim Tao”, which is a mind-body connection that allows him to transfer “Lim Lik” or mind force while in a state of complete muscular relaxation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sigong Chu has mastered the internal forces to the point where he can switch it on at will, and move it through his entire body. He tells a story about how he once had an MRI scan and decided to switch on his ‘Lim Lik’ to see what part of his brain was activating. The doctors told him to stop doing whatever he was doing, because it was throwing the readings out. According to Chu the cerebellum is the part of the brain that activates, which makes a lot of sense because it’s also the part of the brain that controls the synapses to the central nervous system, and a part of the brain we know very little about. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be said that the study of internal martial arts requires a specific kind of abstract intelligence that relies on feeling and intuition. The internal arts deal with “concepts” and “ideas” that can be applied in the body to transfer and deal with force. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn these ideas, the student must be able to feel them in their body, and train them to the point where the neural pathways pertaining to the “idea” are so well mapped out, that they can be triggered with a single thought. The challenging thing for most is to reconcile is that these ideas don’t exist predominantly in the head, they’re directly related to a movement of energy through the body. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When talking with the masters you often hear them talk about “state, not shape”. What this means is that if the idea is working properly, the shape of the body, or the hand technique being applied, is irrelevant. This is interesting, because it shows us that physicality plays a secondary role in generating true force, rather it’s a state of mind that can be triggered. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an wonderful avenue of study, but take care if you’re perusing these skills, because there are countless frauds out there, and probably a handful of people in the world who can actually demonstrate these skills properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="recognising-and-reprogramming-patterns"&gt;Recognising and Reprogramming Patterns&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!-- a ... processor with ... memory
	but still many of us take it for granted, 
Nature reproduces and decays in the form of patterns, and so does our own mind, albeit much more rapidly and responsively. 
Nature reproduces and decays in the form of patterns, and so does our own mind, although it is a much more localised and susceptible medium.
As nature reproduces and decays in the form of patterns, so does our own mind. 
 due to the fact that is's a much more localised and susceptible medium
 grows and decays
Nature takes shape in the form of patterns, as do the thoughts in our mind. 
Just as nature speaks a universal language of recurring geometric patterns and principles[sacred geometry], so does the human mind. 
 [sacred geometry]
Weather or not the same patterns that exist in nature influence our own thoughts is speculative, and not as more useful or relevant as the question of how to identify and reprogram these recurring patterns within our psyche.
 the origin
 of this stimulusow could we possibly take it all in? 
 shapes and 
The more patterning we take on board, the more disconnected we become from , the less free we become; 
 in the brain and body
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In nature, as well as the human mind, we can observe geometric patterns and principles that reoccur - we call it sacred geometry. As energy collides and interacts at the mercy of the &lt;!--variables and constants that comprise the--&gt; laws of nature, it stands to reason that there will be convergent similarities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patterns of the mind, both conscious and unconscious, govern the way we perceive sensory input and stored memories. In essence, reality doesn’t change, but the way we see it does. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thought patterns are learned and enforced on us from from the time of our birth, by our parents, friends, work, and society as whole. Many of these patterns are so ingrained into every day life, that they are absurdly considered by everyone to be “normal”. The deeper you look into your own life and the world around you, the more the matrix of patterns that comprise perceived reality will be exposed. The practice of identifying and understanding the patterns that influence the mind is a worthy pursuit, especially when those patterns may deprive us of our full potential. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more patterns we take on board throughout life, the more disconnected we become from our source, and the less “free” we become. This metamorphosis prevents us from being able to express ourselves truly, and simply “be in the the moment”. Without patterns we would exist in a state of bliss, but the truth is that some patterns are necessary for our very survival, so it’s up to your discretion as to what you want to keep, and what you let go of. The principle of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuroplasticity"&gt;Neuroplasticity&lt;/a&gt; ensures that our mind is ever changing, and we have control over how it develops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="visualise"&gt;Visualise&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step is to visualise the pattern you want to let go of. Mental patterns are constructs of consciousness, so they can be visualised as constructs in the form of shapes and emotions by the way they intersect with, and influence the energetic space in which they exist. The more you can isolate variables and constants which formulate the pattern, the clearer and more aware of the pattern will become&lt;!--, and in turn it's affect on your entire life--&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, calm your mind and relax your body - the deeper your mediative state the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A system is both as simple and complex as the sum of all of its parts&lt;!--[]--&gt;, so start by visualising your life and consciousness as the overall system, and your patterns as the parts which comprise the whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re aware of your pattern and can visualise and it’s constructs, then you’re ready to make your peace and finally let it go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- 
Mental patterns can be visualised as forms and shapes by the way they intersect and influence the energetic space in which they exist. 

-- isolate variables and constants, constructs
The first step to changing subconscious patterning is to gain insight about it through experience, meditation and interaction with others. 

Start by viewing your life as whole, then use reductive thinking? (reverse engineering?) until you arrive at the source of the patterns you're not satisfied with and want to change.


for the people around us
Start with 
so to see your patterning clearly, first view your life as whole, then reverse engineer it part by part until you discover the source of any patterns that you're not satisfied with.
--&gt;

&lt;h3 id="accept"&gt;Accept&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;!--
	can visualise, isolate, and feel
	the constants and variables that formulate it
	This is not about fighting, it's about letting go. Resistance is futile. 
Consciously enter into the process of the pattern that you want to let go of, and be totally aware of
the constants and variables that construct your pattern, and
--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter into a meditative state again, and become aware consciously aware of the pattern that you want to let go of, and how it affects your mind and body. Explore all the parts of your pattern, including the journeys it has taken you on over the course of your life. Wherever this takes you just go with it, and weather you feel pain, fear, rage, or loss, just experience those feelings and allow them to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that resistance is futile; you can’t fight negativity with hatred or more negativity, this is about accepting and letting go. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before long you will feel clear again, like a weight has been lifted - but we’re not done yet! When you’ve accepted your pattern, and dealt with the associated negative feeling and emotions, you’re ready to override your original programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
By accepting your pattern for what it is you stop fighting and become consciously aware of it, an begin to release it's unconscious hold on you.
--&gt;

&lt;h3 id="override"&gt;Override&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overriding your original programming is as simple as doing something that’s completely contradictory to your original programming. The more you do it the better. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is about breaking patterns and limitations, so go nuts. Those that follow the rules their entire live get a life of sub achievement, and a pat on the back with the possibility of a nice retirement fund at the end. Big whoop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that everything that’s considered normal today was outrageous and preposterous at one point in time. At best people will think you’re a savant, and at worst they’ll think you’re an idiot, maybe a little of both, but who really gives a shit what people think anyway!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--Not much more needs to be said - have fun, and above all, be outrageous. This is, after all, about breaking patterns and limitations!


This is as simple as doing something that's contradictory to your original programming. The more you do it the better.

To override your patterning you need to override it by acting contrary to your programming.

The mind processes and stores information visually in the form of images and shapes[], but our perception and the meaning of this stimulus is governed by our conscious and unconscious patterning. For many, the process 

Our belief system is governed by patterns, and many of them have a negative effect on the way we perceive and interact with the world around us. 

Identifying the patterns that govern the mind is a worthy pursuit, especially when it helps us resolve patterns that have a negative impact on our lives. 
These patterns 
--&gt;

&lt;!--
-- desensitisation, coping mechanisms, dumbing down 
can even reprogram itself to fill in the blanks if a memory is too traumatic.

patterns itself to filter non-critical details and experiences, and 
Every day we are bombarded with an insane amount of stimulus, which if we took it all in, would surely drive us insane!  

The mind deals with a traumatic experiences by filtering out the information it can't process, and filling in the blanks with it's own version of events.
This process of desensitisation and patterning helps us cope with reality, and helps (some of) us refrain from shouting at idiots on the street, but it's gone to far when the mind stops testing the boundaries and asking the real questions. 
--&gt;

&lt;!--
, albeit much more rapidly and responsively. 
. It's recognition algorithms 
The human animal thrives under genuine adversity, which forges new pathways and shifts the frame of reference to encompass a greater scope of consciousness.

, which forges new pathways and shifts the frame of reference to encompass a greater scope of consciousness

## Breaking the Rules

This part is about breaking the rules ...
--&gt;

&lt;!--
It's easier to tweak an operational system that it is to build one from scratch, so what are you waiting for? T
--&gt;

&lt;h2 class="no_toc" id="attribution"&gt;Attribution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#banner"&gt;DMT&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="http://studiofeng.net"&gt;Alice Feng&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
